Guide to the John H. Eyer Papers
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
- John H. Eyer papers, 1930-1986; 1950-1974; 3932-001; 18.24 cubic feet (16 boxes) plus 1 oversize folder
  - PAPER COMPANIES, 1948-1974; SERIES 8 (Box-folder 11/16-14/21)
    - Pensions, 1948-1968; Subseries J (Box-folder 13/21-14/17)
      - Marathon Corporation and American Can Corporation Pensions, 1961 (Box-folder 14/3)
      - Menasha Corporation "Report on Proposed Pension Arrangements", circa 1964 (Box-folder 14/4)
      - Pacific Pulp Molding Company Pension Plan, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 14/5)
      - Potlatch Forest, Inc. Pension Plan, 1957-1962 (Box-folder 14/6)
      - Publisher Company Pension Plan: Letter from Eyer, 1966 September 6 (Box-folder 14/7)
      - Rayonier Incorporated Pension Plan, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 14/8)
      - R-W Paper Company Pension Plan, 1958-1967 (Box-folder 14/9)
      - Simpson-Lee Paper Company Pension Plan, 1948-1965 (Box-folder 14/10)
      - Spaulding Pulp and Paper Company Pension Plan, 1956-1962 (Box-folder 14/11)
      - Washington Pulp and Timber Company Pension Plan, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 14/12)
      - Western Kraft Corporation Pension Plan, 1958-1967 (Box-folder 14/13-14)
      - Western Paper Converting Company Pension Plan, 1957-1961 (Box-folder 14/15)
      - Weyerhaeuser Company Pension Plan, 1958-1968 (Box-folder 14/16-17)
    - Arbitration, 1953-1968; Subseries K (Box-folder 14/18-21)
      - Assorted Arbitration Cases, 1956-1968 (Box-folder 14/18-19)
      - Arbitration: Cases Submitted to the Joint Relations Board, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 14/20)
      - Arbitration Interpretations: Company Brief Statements, circa 1964-1968 (Box-folder 14/21)
  - LEGAL CASE FILES, 1959-1968; SERIES 9 (Box-folder 14/22-15/8)
    Contains legal files, including exhibit records from the consolidated 1964 Supreme Court case where the International and the United Papermakers and Paperworkers both filed complaints against the Uniform Labor Agreement Committee, Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers, and AWPPW President William R. Perrin. Records document the formation of the Rank and File Movement for Democratic Action by dissatisfied members of the International in the late 1950s which resulted in the creation of the AWPPW as well as rising tensions between the International and the AWPPW. Files include news clippings, newsletters, and other published material; correspondence; reports; handbooks; Uniform Labor Agreement material; meeting minutes; and depositions and Supreme Court briefs.
    - Exhibit Records: International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers' Rank and File Movement for Democratic Action and Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 14/22)
    - Exhibit Records: International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers and United Papermakers and Paperworkers Members Leaving International, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 14/23)
    - International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers "Complete Report of the Special Investigating Committee" on Allegations Against President Joseph Tonelli, 1960 (Box-folder 14/24)
    - Burt Wells, Exhibit A: Rank and File Movement for Democratic Action's Handbook for Constitutional Reform, 1962 (Box-folder 14/25)
    - Uniform Labor Agreement and Collective Bargaining Information Packet, 1968 (Box-folder 14/26)
    - Exhibit Records: Meeting Minutes of Locals Disaffiliating with the International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers, 1964 (Box-folder 14/27)
    - Exhibit Records: Photographs- Unidentified House and Plaque Awarded to William Perrin, circa 1964 (Box-folder 14/28)
    - Exhibit Records: United Papermakers and Paperworkers and Uniform Labor Agreement, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 14/29)
    - Paul Phillips vs. William Perrin (defendant): Deposition of Sidney W. Grimes Transcript and Exhibit Records, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 14/30)
    - Exhibit Records: Correspondence, International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers Meeting Minutes, Agreements, Press, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 15/1)
    - Exhibit Records: United Papermakers and Paperworkers, International Labor Press Association, and Allegations Against Oregon Labor Press, 1964 (Box-folder 15/2)
    - Exhibit Records: The Amplifier: Voice of the Rank and File Movement for Democratic Action newsletters, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 15/3)
    - Correspondence Between Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers President William Perrin and Pacific Coast Association of Pulp and Paper Mill Workers Director Sidney W. Grimes: Collective Bargaining and Uniform Labor Agreement, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 15/4)
    - Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers, International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers and United Papermakers and Paperworkers: Appellants' Abstract of Record and Brief to the Oregon Supreme Court, 1964 (Box-folder 15/5)
    - Oregon and Washington Circuit and Supreme Court Rulings on United Papermakers and Paperworkers, Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers, and International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers Cases, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 15/6)
    - The Union Watchman Newsletter of International Brotherhood of Pulp, Sulphite and Paper Mill Workers Local 100 and United Papermakers and Paperworkers Local 130 (Camas, WA), 1966-1967 (Box-folder 15/7)
    - Union Democracy in Action newsletters, circa 1962-1966 (Box-folder 15/8)
  - SUBJECT FILES, 1954-1973; SERIES 10 (Box-folder 15/9-39)
    Subseries A contains reference files of labor-specific material, including correspondence, news clippings, reports, and literature from other unions. Subseries B contains reference files specific to investigations into paper mill water pollution in the Puget Sound, including government reports, news clippings and other published material, and drafts of an article written by John Eyer.
    - Labor, 1954-1972; Subseries A (Box-folder 15/9-31)
      - Paper Industry Unions: Mergers and Unifications, 1954-1957, 1972 (Box-folder 15/9)
      - State Federation Conventions, 1954-1958 (Box-folder 15/10)
      - Assorted Labor Organization Correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box-folder 15/11)
      - Farm Workers, 1960 (Box-folder 15/12)
      - Intermediate and Journeyman Mechanics Testing, circa 1960 (Box-folder 15/13)
      - Amalgamated Lithographers Union: News Clippings, 1957-1962 (Box-folder 15/14)
      - Walter Reuther and United Auto Workers Leaving the American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), 1967 (Box-folder 15/15)
      - International Longshore and Warehouse Union, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 15/16)
      - International Woodworkers of America, 1957-1969 (Box-folder 15/17)
      - Postal Workers Unions, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 15/18)
      - Taft-Hartley Compliance and Labor Organizations Registration Form, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 15/19)
      - Assorted Labor Publications, 1956-1966 (Box-folder 15/20)
      - Resources on Women and Labor, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 15/21)
      - United Auto Workers and Auto Negotiations, 1970 July 8 (Box-folder 15/22)
      - Pensions and Social Security: Reference File, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 15/23)
      - Pensions Reference File, 1964-1971 (Box-folder 15/24)
      - Pension Plan Bargaining, 1957-1967 (Box-folder 15/25)
      - American Assembly Conference, Portland, Oregon, 1967 (Box-folder 15/26)
      - Foreign Trade: Import of Japanese Plywood, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 15/27)
      - Oregon Three-Way Workmen's Compensation Law, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 15/28)
      - International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers Literature, circa 1954-1966 (Box-folder 15/29)
      - Western Environmental Trade Association of Washington: Correspondence, Articles, Minutes, Bylaws, 1972 (Box-folder 15/30)
      - "Pulpitis," A Poem About Strikes, Author Unidentified, circa 1960-1970 (Box-folder 15/31)
    - Water Pollution, 1955-1973; Subseries B (Box-folder 15/32-39)
      - Conference Session Summary on Water Pollution in Puget Sound and Strait of Juan de Fuca, 1967 (Box-folder 15/32)
      - Washington Pollution Control Commission and Paper Mill Pollution of the Puget Sound, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 15/33)
      - Washington Pollution Control Commission and Paper Mill Pollution, 1955-1969 (Box-folder 15/34)
      - Eyer's Paper Mill Pollution Articles, Drafts, and Reference Files, 1957-1968 (Box-folder 15/35)
      - Paper Mill Water Pollution, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 15/36)
      - Pollution and Environment News Clippings, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 15/37)
      - Paper Worker Articles on Pollution and Environment, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 15/38)
      - Government Reports on Pollution in Washington State, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 15/39)
  - PERSONAL PAPERS, 1930-1986; SERIES 11 (Box-folder 15/40-16/20)
    Contains material documenting John Eyer’s personal live outside of his work with paper worker unions, including correspondence, studies, and other material from Oregon and Portland-based organizations that Eyer was involved in; family papers, including letters to and from family members as well as marriage and death records of his first wife Alice Eyer; and subject files on Oregon state and national politics, including correspondence from Senators and Representatives as well as material from election and legislative campaigns.
    - Other Organizational Involvement, 1950-1970; Subseries A (Box-folder 15/40-16/7)
      - City Club of Portland: Study of Black Community in Portland, 1950-1959 (Box-folder 15/40)
      - City Club of Portland: Study of Community Colleges and Vocational Programs in Oregon, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 16/1-2)
      - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) of Oregon: Board Minutes, Ephemera, Newsletters, Reports, Correspondence, 1962-1970 (Box-folder 16/3)
      - World Without War Council of Portland: Conference Planning, 1965 (Box-folder 16/4)
      - World Without War Council Executive Board Records, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 16/5)
      - Oregon & Columbia River Labor Assembly for Peace, Trade Union Division of Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy (SANE) Records, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 16/6)
      - Portland Citizens League for Effective City Government, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 16/7)
    - Family, 1930-1976; Subseries B (Box-folder 16/8-12)
      - Eyer Family Personal Correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 16/8)
      - Sara Gamm's [?] Letters to John and Others, 1964-1972 (Box-folder 16/9)
      - Letters Between John and Granddaughter Susan, 1976 (Box-folder 16/10)
      - Alice M. Eyer's Passing: Letters of Sympathy, Obituaries, Marriage and Death Certificates, 1930, 1969 (Box-folder 16/11)
      - Eyer Family: Letters and Genealogical Information, 1935-1972 (Box-folder 16/12)
    - Subject Files: State and National Politics, 1953-1986; Subseries C (Box-folder 16/13-20)
      - Oregon Representative Edith Green's Campaign: Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 16/13)
      - State and Federal Election Campaigns, Political Parties, Legislation, 1954-1973 (Box-folder 16/14)
      - Oregon Senator Wayne Morse, 1953-1968 (Box-folder 16/15)
      - Oregon Senator Richard L. Neuberger, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 16/16)
      - Oregon Representative Charles O. Porter: Correspondence with John Eyer, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 16/17)
      - Oregon Senator Don S. Willner Campaign, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 16/18)
      - Alaska Statehood, 1955-1962 (Box-folder 16/19)
      - Race Relations in Portland, Oregon and Nationally, 1954-1986 (Box-folder 16/20)
- John H. Eyer papers, 1967-1969; 3932-002; 0.21 cubic feet 1 box
  Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers (AWPPW) records, primarily of Local 68 in Oregon City, Oregon, including correspondence, newsletters, notes, and administrative documents.
  Donated by Ross Rieder, November 13, 2011.
  - Controversy Within Association of Western Pulp and Paper Workers: Letters and Articles, circa 1969 (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Uniform Labor Agreement, Industry Wide Agreement, Job Analysis, and Job Training, circa 1968 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Local 68 Newsletters, 1968 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Christmas Card and Letter from the Perrin Family, December 1967 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Local 153 Newsletter, "The Broke Beater", July 1968 (Box-folder 1/5)